EMMANUEL DANIELS

Indianapolis, IN | 317-965-3082 | emmanueldaniels37@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Personal Website

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

As a full-stack web developer with a background in multimedia development and video editing, I place high value on continuously innovating to improve the user experience. My strengths in creativity, problem solving, and collaboration equip me to tackle complex technical challenges and create tailored solutions based on clients' individual needs.

SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Vue.js, Express.js **Frameworks/Libraries:** Ruby on Rails, React, Bootstrap

Databases/Tools: Postgres, APIs, Git, GitHub, AWS, Visual Studio Code

Creative: Bootstrap Studio, Adobe: Premiere Pro, After Effects, Photoshop, Captivate

EDUCATION

Actualize | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

September 2020 - January 2021

A four-month full-stack web development bootcamp. Core technologies included Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and Vue.js. Special emphasis on API-driven development, version control with Git, professional tooling, team collaboration, and continual learning.

School of Motion | Certificate in Design

October 2016

Purdue University | Bachelor of Arts in Film and Visual Studies

August 2006 - May 2011

EXPERIENCE

Project Lead the Way | Multimedia Developer

August 2013 - Present

- Built Interactive City, a learning app that teaches 4th graders about energy usage in communities
 - Built with HTML and CSS on the frontend and jQuery on the back end (repo / demo)
 - Integrated jQuery selectors to allow users to click between different interactive objects
 - Collaborated with clients and designers to determine vision for final product
- Collaborate with the Instructional Media Team to develop effective workflows for cross functional production of ed tech resources
- Develop and deliver visual proposals for instructional content using Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Captivate, Adobe Dreamweaver, Bootstrap Studio methods
- Deployed final renderings to Amazon S3 in preparation for implementation by the final user
- Manage multiple complex projects at a time including video production, frontend development, and project planning for future developments

WXIN TV | Video Editor

September 2011 – August 2013

- Troubleshot urgent technical issues with video equipment and software, ensuring smooth production and timely delivery of 4 newscasts a day
- Edited large quantities of news footage with careful attention to detail to compliance and quality control
- Developed file management system that allowed for quick and effective content sharing between producers, reporters, editors, and directors
- Archived 10 hours of media and post video to File Transfer Protocol sites.

PROJECTS

Tic tac toe game - Play against the computer or a live opponent in this digitized version of a classic game

- Fullstack app built with React.js (<u>repo</u> / <u>demo</u>)
- Integrated CSS Media Queries to allow for layout responsivity to desktop and mobile with a variety of screen sizes
- Added CSS Hover states under buttons to create interactive elements on the page